Park West Village Tenants Association Records TAM.333
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
Park West Village Tenants Association Records
Bulk, 1980-2007
1950s-2007 (Bulk: 1980s-2000s)
TAM.333
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
19.0 linear feet (19 boxes)
The Park West Village Tenants Association represents the tenants of seven apartment buildings on New York City's Upper West Side (372, 382, 392, 400 Central Park West, and 784, 788, 792 Colmbus Avenue), built with with Federal subsidy in the late 1950s. The four Central Park West buildings have become condominiums. The Association seeks to preserve the rent stabilized, middle income status of the three remaining rental buildings, to ensure the proper maintenance of the property, and protect the rights of individual tenants of the buildings, and the tenants as a whole. The collection contains legal materials, government documents, minutes, reports, correspondence, newsletters, subject files, printed ephemera, and clippings. NOTE: This collection is housed offsite and advance notice is required for use.
Park West Village Tenants Association (New York, N.Y.).
Arrangement
Arranged topically.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions. NOTE: This collection is housed offsite and advance notice is required for use.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Park West Village Tenants Association represents the tenants of seven apartment buildings on New York City's Upper West Side (372, 382, 392, 400 Central Park West, and 784, 788, 792 Colmbus Avenue), built with with Federal subsidy in the late 1950s. The four Central Park West buildings have become condominiums. The Association seeks to preserve the rent stabilized, middle income status of the three remaining rental buildings, to ensure the proper maintenance of the property, and protect the rights of individual tenants of the buildings, and the tenants as a whole.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains legal materials, government documents, minutes, reports, correspondence, newsletters, subject files, printed ephemera, and clippings. See the container list, below, for a brief description of the contents of each box of this unprocessed collection. NOTE: This collection is housed offsite and advance notice is required for use.
For additional information, contact: peter.filardo@nyu.edu
Park West Village Tenants Association (New York, N.Y.).; Park West Village Tenants Association (New York, N.Y.).; Housing policy |z New York (State) |z New York.; Housing |z New York (State) |z New York.; Landlord and tenant |z New York (State) |z New York.; Rent control |z New York (State) |z New York.; Tenants' associations |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Contents: Letters dated July 13 and August 11, 1993 concerning a roadway to be constructed on the property including buildings 372, 382, 392 and 400 CPW; A renters guide prepared by PWVTA in September 1992; Copies of covenants concerning the building of Park West Village; The Black Book and other papers pertaining to the Condominium Offering Plan for 392 CPW; The detailed history of the rent reduction and MCI battle between the tenants of 784, 788 and 792 Columbus Ave which began in 1993 and was finally settled in 2005., 1990s-2005 (Box 1)
- Contents: Executive Board minutes and agendas 1991-1992; Legal material re: Balconies in 400 CPW; Fences Fight in CPW buildings in the early 1990s; PWVTA Membership lists 1993-1995, all seven buildings, and letters re conversion; CPW 400 Awning 1995; Early conversion material: brad brewwer argument, survey 5/28/1984, Court Case 372/382; Newsletters 1982-1988; Election 1991; Harassment casev (ambriose) 400 CPW; Roy Harris eviction case, mostly from 792 and 400 in 2000., 1980s-1990s (Box 2)
- Contents: Red Tailed Hawk 1994-1996; Fence issue, CPW buildings; Newsletters - assorted files for 372 CPW and other issues in the 1990s (Box 3)
- Contents: Fliers and newswletters; Some board meeting notes and agendas (Note: many duplicates), undated (Box 4)
- Contents: General - mainly 372 Central Park West, 1990s (Box 5)
- Contents: Intercom Files -784, 788, 792 Columbus Ave; Division of Housing and Community Renewal (DHCR) Rent Reduction Petitions, Complaints, Legal Documents; Tenant Window Depositions; Newsletters, Fliers, 1990s (Box 6)
- Contents: Division of Housing and Community Renewal (DHCR)Legal Documents: Complaints, PAR Exhibits, Security Remands re 784, 788, 792 Columbus Ave; Robert J. Anderson's Comments, 1990s (Box 7)
- Contents: Legal materials: Security Reduction; Window MCI's, 1994-2000 (Box 8)
- Contents: Legal materials: Screening Rent Reductions, Window MCI at 792 Columbus Ave, 1994-2000 (Box 9)
- Contents: Bess Mitchell Files, including Harrassment Case, Board Meetings, mostly from 400 CPW, 1980s-1990s (Box 10)
- Contents: Conversion of 392/400 CPW - including correspondence with Attorney General's Office 1989-1992; Vivian Dee Files (President) 2000-2002, 1989-2002 (Box 11)
- Contents: Vivian Dee Files (President) 2000-2002; Overcharge Cases /Division of Housing and Community Renewal Settlement from 784-788-792 Columbus Ave (Florence Wagener Files): Aptaker, Lisa; Anderson, Linda; Anthony, Peter; Fackler, Peter H. 2000-2004 (Box 12)
- Contents: Overcharge Cases from 784-788-792 Columbus Ave (Florence Wagener Files)/ Division of Housing and Community Renewal Settlement: Feldman, Jason; Fleck, Richard; Kantor, Molly; Glowski, Matt; Lammers, Brent; Nack, Jessica; Nakaniski, Yuki; Pace, William; Purdy, Colin; Rose, Lisa; Resnick, Adam; Santora, Frank; Sorotzkin, Steven; Stepanchek, Tom; Squillacioti, Kathleen; Velyvis, Peter; Williamson, John; Zuckerman, John; Wangh, Anne, 2000-2004 (Box 13)
- Contents: Consolidated DHCR Overcharge Cases (Note: DHCR Final Order is confidential - owner payments may not be quoted but Rent Rollback can be) 2002-2005; Dan Dunbar Files: administrative documents, newsletters, etc. 1997-2007, 1996-2007 (Box 14)
- Contents: Dan Dunbar Files: administrative documents, newsletters, etc. 1996-2007; 400 Central Park West Black Book and 792 Complaint Forms; Legal Files - mainly from Dean Hefner: File 1. Diminution of Services, Comp Agreement drafts, Rent Strike, File 2. MCI 1992-2002, File 3. DHCR Consolidated Overcharge Case 2005; 400 Central Park West Roof Repair and Rent Decrease Case from Winifred Armstrong 1988, 1988, 1996-2007 (Box 15)
- Contents: Legal Files: Early and Current Cases: File 4. Property Agreements, 1950s, Certificates of Occupancy of 784, 788, 792, including parking; Harrassment Case 1987, Challenge to Condo Case 1984, Hardship Case 1979; File 5 Injuction 2006; File 6 MCI 2004-2006; Legal Files from Sylvia Friedrich, 1950s-2006 (Box 16)
- Contents: Parking Case - DHCR Decision, 1989-1989 (Box 17)
- Contents: Administrative documents, fliers, correspondence; Winifred Armstrong Files (Editor of PWVTA Newsletter); Vicki Lawrence Papers, includes Condo Case 1984, 1980s-1990s; 18.0 linear feet (18 boxes) (Box 18)
- Contents: Proposed road thru PWV at 99th St., 1993; Disputed Fence & Awning, 1993; Land Use, 2005-6; Proposed welcome pamphlet, 1996; Playground, 1988-2001; Apartment registrations, 2003; Rent overcharge, 2001-2004; Hardship case, 1978, 1978-2006 (Box 19)